<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>The following day, Mr. Jones arrived.

⁊c̃ 
 Full: 
et cetera 

dĩ 
 Full: dei 

grã 
 Full: gratia 

ꝑ 
 Full: per 

eccl̃ia 
 Full: ecclesia 

p̾benda 
 Full: prebenda 

tempꝰ 
 Full: tempus 

capitl̃i 
 Full: capituli 

Eboraceñ 
 Full: Eboracensis 

dño 
 Full: domino 

Wichtoñ 
 Full: Wighton 

Dunolm̃ 
 Full: Dunelm 

nr̃e 
 Full: nostre 

ꝑpetuo 
 Full: perpetuo 

lib̃alit̾ 
 Full: liberaliter</p>
      <p>It was a diplomatic matter, one that required finesse and tact. The full version of the phrase was et cetera, but in this context, it was shortened to dĩ for brevity's sake.

The lord requested an audience with the bishop, and as they entered the grand hall, he was greeted by the gratia of the ecclesia, the collective body of priests and clergy. The prebenda, a benefice or church living, was conferred upon him as a mark of esteem.

As they made their way to the throne room, the lord couldn't help but feel a sense of nostalgia wash over him. He had spent many years in Eboracensis, the Diocese of York, and it felt like a second home to him. His domino, or coat of arms, was emblazoned on his surcoat, a symbol of his noble lineage.

The bishop, seated upon his throne, smiled warmly at the lord's arrival. "Ah, my dear lord," he said, "I trust your journey here was uneventful?" The lord replied, grateful for the courtesy, that it had been a pleasant one indeed.

As they spoke, the lord's thoughts turned to the matters at hand. He had come to seek the bishop's counsel on a matter of great import, one that required careful consideration and wise deliberation. He had brought with him a copy of the capituli, the decrees of the ecclesia, which he hoped would provide guidance in his decision-making.

The bishop listened attentively as the lord presented his case, offering words of wisdom and advice along the way. As they spoke, the lord felt a sense of gratitude for the bishop's presence in his life, and for the perpetuo bond of brotherhood that united them.

Finally, after much discussion and deliberation, the matter at hand was resolved. The lord departed the bishop's presence feeling grateful and relieved, his thoughts now clearer on the path ahead.</p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>